Baltimore, MD

410.980.9672 (cell) bheussler@gmail.com

## Summary

I am a software developer whose skills and interests lie at the intersection between Semantic Web and Big Data. For over a year I have worked for iNovex Information Systems on the Independent Research and Development program. On occasion, I will provide consulting services to our partner Cambridge Semantics, who provide enterprise level Semantic Web products to commercial customers.

### Experience

# Accumulo Data Integration Prototype

iNovex Information Systems

Software Developer

August 2013 - October 2013

- Handled a variety of data in large volumes by integrating data before it was written to Accumulo, which improved data retrieval at the application layer
- Dynamically applied provenance information based on the PROV-O provenance ontology to all data headed for Accumulo, which provided lineage to all data read from Accumulo
- Integrated structured, semi-structured, and unstructured data using W3C Semantic Web standards, which yielded inherent data layer linkages between like or similar entities from disparate data sets

### **Hive Metadata Extractor**

Cambridge Semantics

Big Data Consultant

June 2013 - July 2013

- Provided metadata to existing query completion and database schema facilities by extracting metadata from Hive using Java and JDBC
- Deployed enterprise software feature adhering to OSGI specification to Anzo Semantic Web Platform

# Economic Volatility Genetic Algorithm

Connecticut College

Student

January 2012 - May 2012

- Foretasted economic volatility using a genetic algorithm, which improved on the traditional technique of regression analysis
- Performed interdisciplinary research under professors Gary Parker (Computer Science) and Purba Mukerji (Economics)

### Education

### Connecticut College

New London, CT

B.A. Major Computer Science, Minor Economics (GPA 3.28)

Aug. 2008 - May. 2012

 Relevant Courses: Computational Intelligence, Artificial Intelligence, Networks, Algorithms, Data Structures, Computer Organization, Topics in Software Development

### University of Nottingham

Nottingham, UK

Study Abroad

Sept. 2010 - Jan. 2011

Relevant Courses: Operations Research and Optimization, Knowledge Representation and Reasoning,
Graphical User Interfaces, Software Engineering Methodologies, Introduction to Formal Reasoning

### Skills

**Languages:** Experience with Java (Proficient), Bash (Competent), SPARQL (Competent), SQL (Competent), Python (Prior Experience), Javascript (Prior Experience) and Scheme (Prior Experience)

Certifications: Oracle Certified Associate, Java SE 7 Programmer

Misc: Experience with Git, Subversion, Maven, Ant, OSGI, Eclipse, Linux, and Windows